Why? Why? Why? Why is that the B-roll it
chose?
Have you been seeing these like science
explainer videos pop up in your feed?
You know, the ones where they're like,
they're like one step away from a Coco
Melon song. The most popular I've seen
is from a Tik Tok account called
Learning with Lyrics. And these guys are
kind of killing it right now. These
things are super viral, like autotuned
songs with lessons that feel straight
out of a high school textbook. And for
some people, this has clearly become a
pretty lucrative side hustle.
Personally, I've never really wondered
how an air conditioner works. But damn
it, I just spent 3 minutes learning all
the ins and outs of climate control
thanks to these stupid addictive videos.
But by now, you've probably guessed it.
I like side hustles and I like money.
So, I want to make one of these accounts
for myself and start raking it in. I
have a pretty solid idea of how these
creators are putting these together,
too. Unfortunately, I just haven't had
the time to create them. So, effective
immediately. No, I'm just screwing with
you. But, I did think it would be a fun
idea to try to recreate these things,
show you exactly how it's done, and
possibly even put the whole thing on
autopilot. So, let's go ahead and dive
in. Here's what we need to do. First, we
need to research the topics. Then, we
need to write the songs. Then we need to
actually create the songs so that
they're poppy and catchy. Then we need
to figure out the visuals for it. And
finally, we need to pull it all together
into a single video. And then it's just
a matter of publishing it to our social
media accounts. Now, there's likely
going to be some manual intervention
required, but let's create one video
first using all of the best tools. And
then once we have one video, we'll try
to pull it all together into a nice
mostly automated system. So, let's go
ahead and get started with research.
Here's
a prompt that I have found works for
actually doing the research and
generating the lyrics all in one step.
Explain to me exactly how a car engine
works. Keep it simple but thorough so
anyone can understand. Give it to me in
the form of a poem. Avoid using
metaphors. I feel like avoid using
metaphors is important because when you
tell it to write a poem, it's going to
try to rhyme as much as possible and
will use metaphors and sort of shift the
meaning of things to get it to rhyme. In
fact, I'm even going to add it does not
have to rhyme. Already done. How a car
engine works. Air enters through the
intake valve. Fuel is sprayed into the
cylinder, etc., etc. I'm not going to
read the whole thing, but this is a
simplified version of how an engine
works.
Now, in my opinion, the best music
generator out there right now is most
likely the videos that are going viral
probably use to generate them. So, for
this specific song, I will use Sunno.
However, we are going to run into an
issue down the line using Suno cuz Suno
doesn't have an API. So, it doesn't
connect to all the various automation
tools where you can just tell SNO to
generate a song within like an automated
workflow, but Sunno generates my
favorite AI music right now. So, we're
going to stick with that for this step
and we'll figure out how to solve that
other problem later. Once I'm in, I
enter some prompts, play with the
settings a bit, which can be fine-tuned
to your personal preferences, and then
hit create. And this is what it spit
out.
Fuel is sprayed.
[Music]
Not bad. But I'm going to go ahead and
generate another variation.
I mean, it's actually pretty catchy, but
it's not quite the style I'm hoping for.
Yeah, I don't like that one either. So,
I did a few rerolls until I finally got
one that I liked. And I really like the
way this one sounds right here. enters
through the intake valve. Fuel is
sprayed into the cylinder. A piston
moves down. We're drawing the mixture
in.
Like that's really kind of what I'm
going for. Very catchy. It's the right
voice. It's slow enough that you can
make out what she's saying. And so one
key inside of Suno is once you find a
style that works and you want to make
sure it sounds like that same musician
in the future. Well, if I come over to
these three dots on the song that I do
like here, I can click on create and
make persona. And then we'll name it Tik
Tok education songs. Now, if I want to
create another song and I want it to
sound very similar in style, I set some
new lyrics. I click on persona. I select
the persona we just created here. So now
every time I go and create a chat GPT
educational poem and pull it into the
lyrics, it'll sound like the same band
or same artist making that song. But now
the next step is quite honestly the most
difficult step. Both if you're doing it
manually and also probably the most
difficult step to automate later. But we
need to get visuals for this whole
thing. I've always thought it would be
kind of cool to start some local
business like a bar or something. But
before any business can actually take
off, you need branding that stands out.
So today, I'm going to design a whole
brand for a modern cocktail bar using
Recraft, the sponsor of today's video.
ReCraft is an AI image generation and
editing tool with over 5 million users
worldwide, trusted by brands like
Netflix, Oglev, and HubSpot. And they
have this new feature called chat mode.
It basically splits your screen in two.
So on the left, you can chat with the
AI, and on the right, you've got a
canvas where your ideas in each
iteration come to life. and it'll
actually remember each iteration as you
work. So, watch this. I just type logo
for a futuristic cocktail bar called
future proof. Sleek typography, neon
glow, minimal modern style. Instantly,
I've got professional logo concepts.
Then I can refine the design using the
chat mode feature. Make it darker, add
more modern accents, try a teal and
magenta color palette. And you can see
that it remembers the first iteration
while updating it with what I asked. And
Recraft isn't just for logos. I can drop
the design it made for me into chat mode
and ask create posters, coasters, and
social visuals in the same style. In a
few seconds, I've got a full brand kit
that I can make merch with and crossost
to all my social media pages. So, if you
want to try this out before anyone else,
join Recraft's new chat mode beta weight
list. The links in the description. Now,
let's get back to the episode.
[Music]
One way we can try to do this is to use
Nvidia. Nvidia has been a sponsor on the
channel in the past. They didn't sponsor
this video, but they have a handful of
features. Now, the feature I've talked
about in my videos in the past has
always been their generative AI videos
where it tries to generate the entire
video. So, I'm actually going to use the
old features that Nvidia was designed
for to see if we can get it to find
stock footage for the script that we
have. All right, so jumping into Nvidia.
First, I choose which social platform I
need assets for. And then I choose what
type of assets I need, the platform, the
type of media, and any additional
guidelines I want to give it. In this
case, I chose Tik Tok stock media, and
then asked it to keep the total video
length to 90 seconds. And a couple of
prompts later, some of it's usable.
Air enters through the intake valve.
Fuel is sprayed into the cylinder. A
piston moves downward, drawing the
mixture in. The intake valve closes. The
piston rises, compressing air and fuel
tightly.
I have no idea what was going on with
some of the music in there, but there
were some visuals that are usable. I
like this visual right here where it
shows the piston go up and then as it
comes down, you know, it gets its fuel
and oxygen and creates an explosion.
Some of this footage has absolutely
nothing to do with what's being said in
the script. For example, this says the
crankshaft spins right here, but it's
literally a still image of a few cogs,
but the cogs aren't spinning. And this I
don't believe is actually a crankshaft.
It almost actually I don't know if
that's the crankshaft or not. I I still
don't know engines very well.
[Music]
Now, the absolute best video generator
of the moment is Sora 2. So, let's take
some of this text and plug it into Sora
2 and see what it generates for us. And
then under describe your video, I'm
going to paste in those three lines.
Make sure we're set on portrait. So,
it's generating in 916. And let's just
generate based on those three lines and
see if it can come up with a decent
visual for us. Now, I'm not totally
getting what I want. This one is, you
know, almost correct. I don't think
these two things overlap each other. And
if this is supposed to be the intake
valve, it's supposed to be, you know,
sealing the gap up here. Not quite
right. The one on the left is a little
more zoomed in. I don't know why there's
air or whatever going below the piston
here. That doesn't make a lot of sense.
But the closeup kind of is cool with it
shooting fuel in, but then it it just
doesn't make a lot of logical sense.
[Music]
The next option would be to find images
of what I actually do want. So, I did a
quick Google search and I found these
screenshots here of like the intake, the
compression, fuel injection, and exhaust
valve. And so, maybe I can get these
images animated for me. So, I'm going to
use Leonardo to generate with V3, but go
ahead and use whatever platform you
prefer for generating with VO. I just
find Leonardo to be the least expensive.
And make sure you do have V3 selected
here. We'll select a start frame. pull
in the image that we just found. And
just for fun, let's have it generate
with the Cling model as well. I'll use
Cling 2.5 Turbo and we'll generate with
that model. See which one does it
better. And well, here's the two sets of
visuals that I got. Neither of them are
very good. V3 kind of added some funky
animation instead of just continuously
spinning like it's supposed to and the
piston continually going up and down and
then cling just kind of sort of went off
the rails completely. Uh so yeah, that's
not quite what I'm looking for. So at
the moment I'm kind of back to the
drawing board on the best way to get the
visuals.
We have some visuals we can use from our
inv video. So maybe we just start there.
This time let's use only generated
clips. So let's go ahead and generate
this. And now we'll have a couple places
to pull from. And then here's the
generated video that it made for us. So
I'm going to mute it because we don't
really need the audio. Uh but if we skim
through it, you can see that it tried to
generate visuals to go along with it.
But these visuals don't really make
sense. They're not accurate to what I'm
talking about. So, if I put these in a
science explainer video, people will not
understand the science from these
visuals, unfortunately. And there's
really I mean, I've skimmed this whole
thing and there's really no good visuals
that I can use cuz all of it is just
sort of nonsense in relation to what I'm
talking about. So, what do I do when I
get hung up on a problem and I can't
figure out the solution? Well, I ask AI.
And so, I went to Perplexity and I said,
"What are the best AI tools to find
B-roll for a script? I don't need it to
be generated videos. B-roll works just
fine. In fact, the videos that we looked
at at the very beginning where they were
making those music science explainers.
They were using B-roll throughout the
whole videos. It was just footage they
collected from around the internet. Most
of it didn't seem generated. So, B-roll
should do the trick. And it suggested
Opus Clip, Submagic, Capwing,
Hypernatural, V, Big View, Visla. And
I've heard of all of these tools. Most
of them I don't think are what I'm
looking for, but OpusClip might be the
solution I'm looking for. I've used Opus
Clip a lot and they've been a sponsor on
this channel in the past. Really, really
good company. I think it's a great
product.
Now, I do see on the Opus Clip web page,
they do offer AI B-roll. And I can see
in my dashboard there is an AI B-roll.
So, it is AI generated B-roll, it looks
like, but it wants a video. So, here's
what I'm going to do. I'm going to jump
over to Cap Cut and we can see our video
has a lot of like black gaps in it where
there's no video footage. I'm just going
to export what we have and there'll be
some sections of just blackness. But at
least I've got a video that I can upload
and it can try to analyze and find
B-roll for. So, let's go ahead and
export this. Click on upload here for AI
B-roll.
Oo, so it gives me an option for AI
generated B-roll and stock B-roll.
That's perfect. I mean, maybe we can run
through both and see what it gives us.
All right. So, here's our B-roll
version, which if I skim through it,
there's some usable stuff, maybe, but
it's not super relevant either. The
exhaust valve opens and it's showing
what appears to be a lathe. No, that's
some part of a machine, but not not what
we're talking about in this video. And
then right here where it says the piston
rises, it shows somebody swimming,
compressing air and fuel tightly. I I
don't know why. Why? Why? Why? Why is
that the B-roll it chose? All right,
let's look at the generated version.
Fuel is sprayed into the cylinder,
but there is some new footage in this
generated version. Air enters through
the intake valve. Shows a picture of an
engine, not super relevant to what's
being said. All right, so I think I've
come to the conclusion that AI is just
not quite there yet to generate all of
the shots for a video like this. We can
have it generate some of them. We could
have Invido and Opus clip and tools like
that go help us round up some B-roll.
But at the end of the day, it doesn't
seem like AI is really good at creating
the imagery for these explainer videos
yet. And if we look at the videos we
talked about at the very very beginning
of this video, that was all stock B-roll
footage that wasn't generated footage.
Hopefully in, you know, 6 months from
now, we'll be able to generate the exact
footage we're looking for. It's just not
quite there yet. So, to get this first
video across the finish line, I'm going
to need to source some more stock
footage. A quick look through my
favorite royalty-free sites, and I'm
able to pull everything I need to make a
compelling explainer video. From there,
I throw everything into Cap Cut, use
their auto captioning feature, and hit
export on my first viral masterpiece.
Fuel is sprayed into the cylinder. A
piston moves down. We're drawing the
mixture in.
The intake valve closes, the piston
rises, compress.
I mean, I think it came out pretty good.
You could watch that video and listen to
the song and see the visuals and kind of
know how a engine works. But that's not
good enough for me. I am dead set on
figuring out how to better automate
this.
It may not be as good as what we just
saw, but I want to get pretty dang
close. So, let's build an automation for
this. I'm going to play with a tool
called Glyph. It's a tool I haven't
spent a lot of time with, but I flew out
to New York and met the Glyph team a
couple weeks ago, and they showed off
their new agent mode while I was
visiting with them, and I was pretty
impressed. And I think I might be able
to get most of what I want done just by
building an agent inside of Glyph. So,
let's try it. So once you're inside of
Glyph, we can come over to agents here,
and we can actually see a ton of
different agents that have already been
pre-built. There might even be one
that's already pretty close. Let's see.
Music video creator. Generate infinitely
long one-take videos with Cling 2.5.
Selfie music studio. Make yourself rap,
sing, dance. But you know what? I'm just
going to build one from scratch since I
know exactly what I'm looking for. So
let's create an agent. Once inside
Glyph, I choose the chat engine and run
through all the instructions it needs to
oneshot this task. This includes telling
it the order in which to run through the
tasks and more importantly which
platforms and tools to use. And I'm
choosing everything. I'm thinking that
if I cast a wide enough net, I'm bound
to catch a nice fish. Okay, so we're
actually on to something here. So, it
used Clling to generate this video here.
It added subtitles and then it overlaid
the song. All I did was give it this
original prompt and it did all of this
stuff for us. Generated the music,
generated some images. This is the
actual song which I'll play in just a
second. Generated the starting frame,
generating an ending frame, animating
the starting frame to the ending frame,
adding the subtitles, and then
overlaying the music on top of it. And
here's what we got. Now, it only
generated 10 seconds, and the visuals
aren't great, but it's strung together a
lot of these steps really, really well.
That's what I'm impressed by.
On a circuit board, tiny city of light,
copper traces our road, sending signals
just right. Resistors slow it down the
faster. Smooth the flow of the chip. Is
the brain saying, "Ready, set, go."
But it does ask me at the bottom, want
me to make a longer 30 to 45se secondond
version with a chorus and more scenes?
Hell yeah, I do. Okay, so we got a 44
second song. My instructions were not to
use V3, and it killed a crap ton of
credits, as we can see down here. And
then it went to add subtitles to the
video and it says it's a 44 second
video. I'm skeptical.
On a circuit board, tiny city of light.
Copper trace is a roads guiding currents
in flight. Power needs a reg.
All right. I guess I was right to be
skeptical on that one.
[Music]
Okay, I think I know how I'm going to do
this now. I'm going to use Mine Studio.
I think I can build an automation like a
workflow that with all the steps using
Mine Studio. Let's see if we could do it
here. So, build new agent. Now, I've
used Mind Studio a lot in the past for
setting up these kinds of agentic
automations. It's really clean and
pretty easy to use. So, I add each step
of the process starting with making the
song. Take a user inputed topic,
research, generate the lyrics, and turn
that into a piece of art. Not slop art.
Please let this one be art. It seemingly
worked. Let's listen to a snippet here.
Flat insulating boards with copper
veins, fiberglass core for strength and
contains guide the current flow.
Not a huge fan of the style of the song.
So, let's go to our text to speech our
11 labs. If I was to give it more
instructions, like create a song, create
a kids song that's poppy and catchy with
a female singer's voice. All right,
here's what we got.
Amazing.
[Music]
I kind of got it working by bringing
this down to 900 characters. 2000 was
still a little bit too long of a song.
And then on the text to speech model,
change the length to 30 seconds instead
of 45 just for the sake of speed. A
circuit board is a rigid base.
All right, now comes the hardest part,
and that's trying to get the visuals to
go over the song itself. So, I'm
starting with V3 fast in order to save
some time and money on the generations.
But I'm feeling like my frugality may
come back to haunt me.
I'm also thinking that if I split up the
lyrics into chunks, I should be able to
get separate clips for each part of the
song. I think then I'm going to use Mine
Studio to automate the assembly of each
component of the video. Couple of final
touches. And here's what it generated
for us. A 30 second video with a song,
not as good as Sudo's song, and it did
put visuals throughout the whole thing.
[Music]
A circuit board BCP
holds parts and links them
links them.
Fiberglass carries thin copper traces in
layers
and holes where
it did all the steps. I just can't get
the visuals to look the way I want them.
The choice is going to be you you get
all the way up to where you have the
song created and then you go in, pull
the visuals and sort of splice them all
in where you want them or you can get a
fully automated music video that's
generated with AI. The visuals just
aren't going to be amazing if you're
trying to get it to be like that
explaining how something works. There
are ways to do it with AI. Whether those
ways are faster than just sourcing
B-roll right now, I I don't think so.
But yeah, for this style of music video,
you could do a big bulk of it with AI,
but at some point you're going to have
to edit the video together yourself or
hire somebody to edit the video because
I just I don't see a way to just
generate that whole process yet.
Hopefully, you did learn something. I
mean, we did figure out how to make that
style of video. It just wasn't all AI. I
had to source some of the videos. And
then we also figured out how to use some
pretty cool automation tools. Although
we didn't get our end result, I have a
much better idea of how to use glyph now
and some cool workflows in Mind Studio
that I didn't know I can do before. So,
still learned a lot along the way. I
guess at the end of the day, if this got
your wheels turning about some things
that you can create, you know, maybe
it's not trying to make educational
music videos with uh perfect B-roll to
go along with the music. Maybe it's, you
know, Facebook video ads for your
company or a silly meme generator that
generates brain rot slop. It'll probably
be pretty good at that if that's what
you're going for. But to get that
educational style video, still a little
bit of work involved, meaning we're
probably not going to see the internet
flooded with them quite yet. But that's
what I got for you. Thank you so much
for tuning in. If you like videos like
this and you want to see me dig deeper
and explore a lot of other AI tools,
make sure you like this video, subscribe
to this channel. I'll make sure more
stuff shows up like this in your feed.
Really appreciate you hanging out,
nerding out, and hopefully I'll see you
in the next one. Bye-bye. A circuit
board BCP
holds parts and links them
links there.
Fiberglass carries thin copper traces in
layers, pads and holes, marks